Hey...
（マダラ）よう！
話でもどうだ？　うずまきナルト。
How about we talk, Naruto Uzumaki?
（ナルト）てめえは！
You!
A Rasengan right off the bat, huh?
（マダラ）いきなり　螺旋丸か。
効かないのは知っているだろ。
You know it doesn't work on me, right?
（ヤマト）ナルトは　じっとしてなね。
Naruto, you just stay put.
さすが　写輪眼のカカシだ。
速い…。
As expected, Sharingan Kakashi.
You are fast.
（カカシ）そう簡単に　ナルトに
手は出させやしないよ。
We won't let you get your hands on
Naruto that easily, Madara Uchiha.
うちはマダラ。
だったら　さっきの俺のセリフは
聞いているだろ。
You did just hear my last line,
didn't you?
この　うちはマダラには
一切の攻撃は通用しないと。
No attacks work against
Madara Uchiha.
あなたが体を消しているのか→
I don't know if you are
merely erasing your presence
霊体化しているのかは
わからないが→
or if this is an astral projection,
ナルトを捕まえるときは
体を実体化する必要がある。
but I know it's necessary for you
to manifest physically
in order to capture Naruto.
でなければ
ナルトをつかむことはできない。
Otherwise, you couldn't actually
grab him.
だから　そこを狙う。
We'll aim for that.
（ヤマト）もう　ここは　僕のテリトリーだ。
This here is now my territory.
ククク…　俺は　別に
簡単にいくとは思っていないよ。
I never thought it would be easy.
You see, I have my own plan.
俺にも計画ってものがある。
それよりも　今は話がしたい。
But right now, I'd rather talk.
話だと？
Talk?
そうだ　ペイン長門を
裏切らせたものは何なのか？
Yes. What was it that made Pain, Nagato,
turn into a traitor?
Naruto... You have aroused my curiosity.
ナルト　お前に興味がわいてきた。
そんなことはどうだっていい！
Who cares about something like that?!
てめえは
サスケをどうするつもりだ！
What do you intend to do
with Sasuke?!
サスケのことを教えろ！
Tell me about Sasuke!
サスケねぇ…。
Sasuke, huh?
いいだろう。　なら話してやる。
Very well. I'll tell you.
忍世界の憎しみ　恨みに
骨の髄まで侵された男…。
About the man whose hatred
of the ninja world
runs through his bones
to his very core.
うちはサスケの話を。
About Sasuke Uchiha.
サスケの話をするうえで
イタチのことは避けては通れない。
Sasuke's story cannot be told
without mentioning Itachi.
まずは　イタチの真実から聞け。
So first, hear the truth about Itachi.
（エー）サスケは　どこだ？　答えろ！
Where is Sasuke?! Answer me!
（ゼツ）しようがないなぁ。
You leave me no choice.
I'll give you a hint, so...
じゃあ　ヒントでも出す…。
シー　始めろ！
（シー）はっ！
Shee! Begin!
Yes sir!
（メイ）何も殺すことはないでしょう。
捕まえて尋問すれば→
You didn't have to kill him.
We could have taken him in
and tortured him
暁の情報が
手に入ったかもしれないのに。
into revealing intel about the Akatsuki.
（我愛羅）暁に口を割るような
やつはいない。
No one in the Akatsuki talks.
They are extremely loyal.
筋金入りのやつらだ。
（ミフネ）オキスケ　ウラカク！
すぐに　サスケを捜すよう命を出せ。
Okisuke, Urakaku.
Issue an order to search for Sasuke.
それと　第二戦闘態勢を発令だ。
And issue a Number 2
battle-ready state alert.
（２人）はっ！
- Yes, sir!
雷影様！
霧の隻眼！
Lord Raikage!
You! One-eyed Mist!
お前は　火影を見張ってろ！
Watch the Hokage!
シー　ダルイ！　行くぞ！！
Shee! Darui!
Come!
（ダルイ）机とか壁とか　すみませんね。
I'm so sorry about the desk
and the wall.
こら　ダルイ　そんなことはいい。
行くぞ！
Darui, never mind that. Let's go!
（オオノキ）
まったく　荒っぽいやつじゃぜ。
What a violent fellow.
雲のきかん坊は
五影になってもそのままじゃな。
The Cloud's rascal hasn't changed
even as a Kage.
（ウラカク）第二戦闘態勢　発令。
侵入者　うちはサスケを捜せ。
Number 2 battle-ready state alert.
Search for the intruder, Sasuke Uchiha.
塔入り口に　三小隊を急派。
防護線を作れ。
Dispatch three squads
to the tower entrance.
Create a line of defense.
[無線]了解。
Roger.
行くぞ！
Move out!
（香燐）これは！？
What's this?!
（サスケ）どうした　香燐？
What is it, Karin?
侍たちの動きが
慌ただしくなった。
The Samurai's movements
have suddenly become flurried.
うちらを探しているみたいだ。
I think they're looking for us!
（水月）え～　どうして？
What?!
But we didn't do anything to be spotted.
僕ら
見つかるようなマネしてないよ。
（重吾）ゼツ…　あいつだな。
I bet it was Zetsu.
すでに逃げたか…。
They're already gone.
Racing Lightning
駄目だ…
数が多すぎる。
It's no good.
There are too many of them.
これじゃ　すぐに見つかって
捕まるぜ。
We'll be found in no time and captured.
Zetsu, was it? I'll get him for this!
ゼツとかいったっけか…
あいつ　覚えてろよ！
はっ！
あんなふうに　チャクラを使うのか…。
So that's how they use chakra?
I'm very irritated right now.
俺は　今　いらだっている。
If you attack, I'll show no mercy.
来るなら
手加減はできそうにない。
I would say the same to you!
それは　こちらとて同じ！
He repelled it?
弾いたのか！？
我々の剣技と似ている！
It's similar to our sword technique!
香燐…　侍の感知はもういい。
Karin, you don't have to monitor
the Samurai anymore.
ダンゾウの居場所を感知しろ。
Focus on Danzo's location.
But what about the Samurai?
どうすんだよ　侍は…。
侍は　俺が相手をする。
とにかく　ダンゾウだ。
I'll deal with them.
Just find Danzo.
Huh?!
えっ！？
《サスケのチャクラが…　違う！》
Sasuke's chakra is different!
うお～！
ぐわっ！
うわっ！
うおっ！
Hey... After all his warnings telling me
not to kill anyone...
あいつ　僕には　あれだけ
殺すなって言ったくせに…。
これは…。
This is...
《今までのサスケじゃない…。
He's not the same Sasuke
as before.
呪印状態２のときより
濃いなんて…。
He's more intense than when he is
in the Curse Mark Second State.
それに…。
And much...
冷たい…》
colder.
仲間がいたのか…。
He's not alone!
かなりの勢いで
チャクラを消してるチャクラがあります！
There's one chakra that is erasing
many other chakras!
No doubt it's coming from Sasuke!
おそらく　それがサスケのものかと。
どっちだ！？
Which way?!
この真下です！
Right below us!
《雷影様　それは…》
Lord Raikage, you're not going to...
《何か来る！　でかい！》
Something's coming. And it's huge!
なんだ！？
What is that?!
小僧！
Hey brat!
憤怒の恐怖を教えてやる！
I'm going to teach you
the fear of true fury!
（重吾）サスケ！
１人で突っ込むな！
Sasuke! Don't go in alone!
《冷静さを欠いている…》
He's lost his cool!
水遁　水陣壁！
Water Style: Water Wall!
《こいつか！》
His attack, huh?
Lightning Style: Emotion Wave!
雷遁　感激波！
ボス　こいつ情報どおり雷の性質に
間違いないみたいっすね。
Looks like the intel was right, Boss.
This guy seems to possess
a Lightning Chakra Nature.
それに火も持っている
じきに火遁も使うだろう。
Plus he has a Fire Chakra Nature.
He's bound to use Fire Style
at some point.
Darui, keep Water Style
ready at all times.
ダルイ　水遁の用意は常にしておけ。
あぁ。
Yeah.
なんか　サスケの情報
漏れちゃってない？
Doesn't it look like
they have intel on Sasuke?
Hey, the one in the middle.
Isn't that...?
おい　あれ　中央のあいつ
あれってまさか…。
こいつら　雲隠れの上忍
中央のでかいのは雷影だ。
They're Hidden Cloud jonin.
The huge one in the middle
is their Raikage.
簡単には通してもらえない。
They won't let us pass easily.
応援を頼む　サスケにやられた！
Seeking reinforcements!
Sasuke got us!
動きを止める！
I'll stop him!
何か来るぞ！
Something's coming!
雷幻雷光柱！
Lightning Illusion: Flash Pillar!
目くらましか！
Is he trying to blind us?!
サスケ！
Sasuke!
《そんな…》
No!
重吾　怯むな！　これは幻術だ！
Jugo, don't waver.
This is a genjutsu.
Not bad, Sharingan. However...
《やるな　写輪眼　だが…》
幻術を見抜いたとしても
遅いわ！
You may have seen through
the genjutsu, but it's too late!
サスケ！
Sasuke!
♪～
あぁ　クソ…　僕の首切り包丁が！
Damn it! My Executioner's Blade!
八尾と戦ったとき
切れ目を入れられていたからな。
It'd already gotten cracked
against the Eight-Tails.
It can't be helped.
助かった…　水月　ナイス！
S-Saved. Nice, Suigetsu!
お前ら　余計なことを。
Who told you to butt in?
せっかく
助けに出てきてやったのにさ→
We came to help you,
and this is what we get?
何だよ　その言い草
君らしいけど。
Although that's just like you.
忍とは雑な戦いをする
なんてやつらだ！
Ninja sure fight rough.
They're crazy!
シー　他に仲間がいるのか
辺りを調べてみろよ。
Shee, check and see if they've got
any other allies around.
I don't want to worry about
more popping in.
次々に出てこられちゃ
だるくてやってらんねぇ。
確か　もう１人いたはずだ。
I'm sure there was one more.
しかし　そっちに集中すると
戦闘には参加しにくいんだが。
But if I focus on that one,
it'll be hard to stay in the fight.
お前はいらねえよ
ボスと俺でやっからさ。
We don't need you.
Boss and I can handle them.
《やばい！
このままダンゾウを捜してたら→
Uh-oh! If I keep searching
for Danzo like this,
I'll be the one found by that Shee.
あのシーってのに
見つかっちまう！》
香燐のやつ
チャクラ消して隠れるよ　たぶん。
Karin will probably extinguish
her chakra and hide.
そういう能力だから。
She's got that ability.
（重吾）あのうしろの男は
感知タイプだな。
That guy in the back is probably
a Sensory-Type ninja.
倒すしかない。
We have to take him down.
俺がやる。
I'll do it.
（オキスケ）また動き出すということは
なさそうです。
It doesn't look like he'll be moving
around again.
Sir Ao, please confirm
青殿　火影の瞳術が　まだ継続中か
確認していただきたい。
if the Hokage's Ocular Jutsu
is still engaged or not.
No. The flow of chakra in
his Chakra Network is very calm.
（青）いや　今は
経絡系のチャクラの流れも穏やかだ。
術は解いている。
The jutsu is undone.
Relax. It's not a jutsu I can use
that many times in a day.
（ダンゾウ）安心しろ　日にそう
何度も使える瞳術ではない。
I'll decide that. For you are a man
who cannot be trusted.
それは　こちらで判断する。
あんたは
信用できない男だからな。
まさか　白眼が
他にもれていたとはな。
I never imagined the Byakugan had fallen
into outside hands.
Had the traitor been a Hyuga
from the Hidden Leaf,
木ノ葉の日向の裏切り者なら
すぐに殺していたところだ。
he would have been killed immediately.
あんたは秘密を知った俺を→
You are probably planning to dispose of me
for learning your secret,
いずれ処理するつもりで
いるんだろうが→
but that will not happen.
そうはいかんぞ！
そのときは私が戦う。
I shall fight you at such a time.
四代目水影を操っていた
術と　その瞳力。
Because there may just be a connection
between the jutsu that had control
over the Fourth Mizukage
何か関係あるかもしれないからね。
and your ocular powers.
Lord Hokage, ninjutsu is prohibited
in this room.
火影殿　ここでは忍術はご法度。
信用を欠いてしまったな。
You have lost your credibility.
Even if you hadn't resorted to this,
I may have chosen you, you know.
こんな手を使わずとも　拙者は
あなたに決めたやもしれぬのに。
（ダンゾウ）やもしれぬでは　困るのだ。
"May have chosen" was unacceptable.
わしは　忍の世界を守るために
どんな手でも使うつもりだ。
I was prepared to use
any means necessary
in order to protect
the world of the ninja.
この世界は
ひとつになるべきなのだ。
This world must become one.
かつて　初代火影　柱間が→
In the same way that
the First Hokage, Hashirama,
一族をまとめて
里をつくったように。
united our people and
founded our village.
今度は　里をまとめ
忍世界をひとつにする。
This time, I shall unite the villages
and create one ninja world.
There is no way this ninja world can
be united through discussions alone.
話し合いで　この忍の世界が
ひとつになることはない。
理想を実現するには
時間がかかるもんじゃぜ。
It takes time to realize one's ideals.
Impatience makes one lose sight of
his surroundings and invites failure.
焦れば　まわりが見えず
失敗を引き起こす。
今のお前だ。
That's you right now.
（ダンゾウ）時間をかけて
道徳的にやっていては→
Nothing will change by
working slowly and ethically.
何も変わらん。
Sooner or later, the Akatsuki will
destroy the ninja world.
いずれは　暁に
忍世界を潰されてしまうだろう。
Well, that is just an impossible dream.
（オオノキ）まぁ　所詮そんな
理想は無理な話じゃぜ。
よかれと思っても
結果　不信を生み→
It may sound noble, but ultimately,
it will only breed distrust,
ill will and resentment.
わだかまりを生み　憎しみを生む。
ダンゾウ　今はお前の
言ってることすら信用できん。
Why Danzo, we don't even trust
your words at this point.
信用があろうとなかろうと
結果は　必要だ。
Whether I am trusted or not,
it's the outcome that is essential.
（我愛羅）
互いを信じることができない。
Unable to trust each other.
If that is the world...
それが　世界
それが　人間だとするなら→
If that is being human,
there is no future.
未来はないな。
What is it you want to say?
何が言いたい？
Understanding and trusting
in one another...
分かち合うこと　信じること。
それをやめたら
世界に残るのは恐怖だけだ。
If we lose that, only fear will remain
in the world.
道徳を考慮しない
やり方やあきらめは→
Acting with no regard for what is right...
resigning oneself...
I find such things hard to
accept these days.
今の俺にとって
受け入れがたいものになった。
難しいことを簡潔に言うのう。
For a kid who knows nothing
about governing a village yet,
you speak easily about
difficult matters.
里を治めることを
まだ　何も知らぬガキが。
今のうちに
聞きたいことがあったら→
Now's your chance to
ask anything you'd like.
何でも質問しろ。
先輩として何でも答えよう。
As your seniors, we're willing
to answer any questions you have.
のう　ダンゾウ。
（カンクロウ）なんだと　じじい！
Right, Danzo?
How dare you, you old geezer!
（テマリ）よせ　カンクロウ。
これでも土影　他里の長だぞ。
Don't, Kankuro.
He's still Tsuchikage.
The leader of another village.
（赤ツチ）
あいつ　これでもと言っただに。
Did she just say "still"?
Ignore them.
（黒ツチ）ほっとけ。
なら　ひとつだけ問う。
Then let me ask you this.
Sure. I will answer anything, kid.
あぁ　何でも答えてやるぞ。
若造。
あんたたちは　いつ己を捨てた？
When did you all forsake yourselves?
《純粋な子…》
What a pure-hearted child.
へっ。
さて　我愛羅。　私らはどうする？
So Gaara, what will we do now?
うちはサスケ奪還任務では
木ノ葉には協力したが→
We cooperated with
the Hidden Leaf on their mission
to rescue Sasuke Uchiha.
But he's now descended
to joining the Akatsuki.
今は　暁に成り下がった輩だ。
うちはサスケか…。
Sasuke Uchiha...
おい　護衛を置いて
先に行くな！
Hey! Don't go off without your guards!
Gramps, he's scored a point on you.
じじい　一本取られたな。
うるさいわい！
Shut it!
Lord Tsuchikage...
What do we do?
土影様　わいらはどうするだに？
戦闘しに行くか？
Shall we go forth to battle?
アホ！　腰痛が悪化したら
どうするんじゃぜ！
Fool! What if the back pain gets worse?!
あたいは　デイダラ兄をやったっていう
サスケが見たい。
But I want to see this Sasuke who
supposedly took down Bro Deidara.
好きにせい。　ただし雷影に
巻きこまれたら死んでしまう。
Do as you please.
Just remember, if you get caught
in the Raikage's crossfire,
you'll die.
手は出すな。
よっしゃ！
So stay out his way.
Gotcha!
What about you, Akatsuchi?
赤ツチは　どうする？
I'll stay with Lord Tsuchikage,
in case he has trouble with his back.
わいは　土影様の腰に
何かあったらいけねえから→
一緒にいるだに。
じゃあな。
Later, then.
（フー）ダンゾウ様
写輪眼　回収のため→
Lord Danzo, please allow
one of us to go forth
in order to retrieve the Sharingan.
我々のどちらかを
下へ行かせてください。
You Hidden Leaf will stay as you are!
Lord Raikage has so ordered!
あんたたち　木ノ葉は
そのままでいてもらおう！
雷影殿にそう託された。
フー　トルネ　よせ！
Foo, Torune...don't.
ここは　おとなしくしておく。
We will play nice for now.
♪～
ヒャハハハハ！
ぶっ殺してやら～！
I'll kill 'em!
見た目よりも　性格の変わりようが
すごいな　こいつ。
His change in personality is
more surprising than his appearance.
集中しろ！　そいつ
とんでもないチャクラ　してやがるぞ！
Focus! This guy's chakra is ridiculous!
ヒャハ～　ハ～！
ついに　殺人衝動バリバリ
自分から出しちゃったよ。
Jugo voluntarily gave in to
his killer impulse this time.
重吾のやつ。
僕らのこと
味方って　理解できてんのかな？
You think he still remembers
that we're on his side?
さぁ…　どいつからだ～！
Now then, who's first?!
フン。
図にのるな！
Don't get cocky!
♪～
《もらった！》
You're mine!
♪～
いいの　持ってるね。
Nice blade you got there.
折れたからって
こりゃ　やれねえよ。
Can't have this just
because yours broke.
♪～
まずは　一匹。
One down.
写輪眼ごときに　とらえられる
わしではないわ！
You can't take me down with
a mere Sharingan!
《雷影様の体内の
神経伝達　反射のスピードは→
Lord Raikage's nerve transmission
and reaction speed
are on par with that of
the Leaf's Yellow Flash.
黄色い閃光に劣らない。
Impressive that these guys are
keeping up as well as they are!
こいつら
よく　ついてきてるほうだ。
しかし　反射を活性化する
雷遁チャクラを　まとった以上→
But Lord Raikage has manipulated
Lightning Style Chakra
to augment his reflexes.
写輪眼でも　追いつけない！
Not even the Sharingan will
be able to keep up with him.
それに　まだ…》
Plus, there's still...
ぬっ！？
死ね～！
Die!
ボス！
ゼロ距離！
Boss!
From point-blank range!
くっ！
やったか！？
Did he get him?!
《あいつ　雷影様の一撃を食らって
生きていたとでも！？》
He took Lord Raik
あぁっ！？
うあっ！
《こ…　これは…　幻術か…》
《こいつら　仲間の攻撃を
うまく　陽動に当ててきやがる。
俺としたことが！　くそ～！》
《体が…　動かない…》
シー！
シー！　なに　寝てやがる！
立てって！
ヒャハハハ～！
殺した！　殺してやったぜ～！
《重吾のやつ
意外と　役に立つじゃねえか。
よし　今なら感知されない。
今のうちに　ダンゾウを！》
次は　どいつだ～！
♪～
（くもじい）もしもし
そこのあなた→
たまには　空から日本を眺めてみる
というのはどうじゃろ？
今回は　千葉県のローカル線
銚子電鉄と小湊鐵道。
更には　千葉モノレールの３線じゃ。
（くもみ）え？
３つも見られるんですか？
ローカル線って
のどかでいいんですよね。
もちろん　いつものように
線路沿いには→